all right I'm gonna jump over to our
tamam ben üstünden atlayacağım
single board computer unboxing zone here
burada tek kartlı bilgisayar unboxing bölgesi
and here is a box that says hoe drive
ve işte çapa sürücü yazan bir kutu
and so some of you know kind of by
Ve bazılarınız bunu bir nevi biliyor.
looking on the Odroid forums what is
Odroid forumlarına bakmak ne
about to occur this ladies and gentlemen
bu bayanlar ve baylar gerçekleşmek üzere
is a box containing a no droid n to the
bir no droid n içeren bir kutu
brand-new board from heart colonel the
albay yepyeni kurulu
Odroid n2 is a new generation single
Odroid n2 yeni nesil bekar
board computer that's more powerful more
daha daha güçlü gösterge paneli
stable more faster more faster faster er
kararlı daha hızlı daha hızlı daha hızlı er
somebody correct me more work it's more
Biri beni daha çok çalışsın düzeltir
faster than the n1 it's more faster than
n1’den daha hızlı
anything that I think Oh droid has
sanırım bir şey Oh droid
brought out just yet ok so this board
sadece henüz tamam bu yüzden çıkar kurulu
has the ARM Cortex a 73 CPU cluster it
ARM Cortex 73 işlemci kümesine sahiptir.
also has a dual core cortex a53 cluster
ayrıca çift ​​çekirdekli bir korteks a53 küme vardır
with a new generation mal eg 52 GPU so
Yeni nesil bir mal ile örneğin 52 GPU
it's super powerful 6 cores what have I
süper güçlü 6 çekirdekli ben neyim
got in the Box I'm getting right in here
kutuya girdim ben tam buraya geliyorum
I really want to just dive right in I've
Ben gerçekten sadece dalmak istiyorum
got a USB Wi-Fi dongle I've got a 16
bir USB Wi-Fi dongle'ı var 16
gigabyte emmc storage card and I'm gonna
Gigabyte emmc hafıza kartı ve ben yapacağım
just kind of set that aside is that
bir kenara koymak bir tür
cruel of me is that cruel oh I can't
Beni zalim o kadar zalim ah yapamam olduğunu
wait to get into this it's got 1.8
Bu almak için bekleyin 1.8 var
gigahertz without thermal throttling
termal kısma olmadan gigahertz
think about that for a second on a
bunu bir saniye için düşün
single board computer Oh what is this ah
tek kartlı bilgisayar Ah bu ah nedir
we've got the us adapter they were kind
biz onlar tür bizi adaptörü var
enough to think of the fact that I am
benim olduğumu düşünecek kadar
here in Canada because I'll get y'all
Burada Kanada'da çünkü hepinizi alacağım
betcha
Betcha
yeah the power adapter here is gonna
evet burada güç adaptörü olacak
need that guy let's see here
İhtiyacımız olan adam burada görelim
so what do we have as far as power goes
peki iktidara gelince elimizde ne var
let's put that all right
hadi her şeyi koyalım
come on get on there
hadi oraya
somehow someway ladies and gentlemen
her nasılsa bir şekilde bayanlar baylar
this bad boy is gonna clip on here and
bu kötü çocuk buraya takılacak ve
give me power I guarantee you that is
bana güç ver sana garanti ederim
the case but it makes a really bad TV to
durumda ama bu gerçekten kötü bir TV yapar
actually demonstrate it for the first
aslında ilk defa
time so you want me to do that that's
zaman bu yüzden bunu yapmamı istiyorsun
gonna plug into this it's gonna allow me
buna bağlanacak bana izin verecek
to plug that into my wall this is a 12
onu duvarıma takmak için bu 12
volt mm and milli ampere mm amp yeah
volt mm ve milli amper mm amp evet
right to amp
amp hakkı
there we go this is the chassis we've
orada biz bu biz ettik şasi olduğunu gitmek
seen something similar to this on the
buna benzer bir şey gördüm
Odroid hc1 wait a minute this looks
Odroid hc1 bu görünüme bir dakika bekleyin
really tiny for an end to I've seen the
sona ermesi için gerçekten küçük gördüğüm için
pictures on their website and it looks
kendi web sitesinde resimler ve görünüyor
huge
Kocaman
can it really be that small this is
Gerçekten bu kadar küçük olabilir mi
rhetorical it's just - because I'm
retorik sadece - çünkü ben
excited this is a lot smaller than I was
heyecanlı bu benden çok daha küçük
expecting
bekliyor
oh look at that there you have it
ah işte başardık şuna bak
ladies and gentlemen I'm just gonna
bayanlar baylar ben sadece
bring that up to the camera just so you
Bunu kameraya getir ki sadece sen
can get a quick little glimpse at the
hızlı bir bakışta alabilirsiniz
Odroid n - what do we notice first of
Odroid n - İlk önce neyi fark ediyoruz?
all these are blue 4 USB 3.0 full-sized
tüm bunlar mavi 4 USB 3.0 tam boyutlu
ports that is perfect
mükemmel olan portlar
we've got HDMI 4k 60 out we've got
HDMI 4k 60 çıkışımız var
Gigabit Ethernet we've got the barrel
Gigabit Ethernet varil var
adapter input are you ready for this
adaptör girişi bunun için hazır mısın
this is kind of exciting for those of us
bu bizim için biraz heyecan verici
who have a lot of bricks laying around
etrafında döşeme birçok tuğla var
this will take seven point five volt
bu yedi nokta beş volt alacaktır
this will take I think it's like up to
Bu sürecek kadar bence
20 volts this will take a like a wide
20 volt bu geniş alacak
range of adapters 12 volt to amp is the
Adaptör çeşitleri 12 volt amper
recommended voltage and amperage but
önerilen voltaj ve amper ancak
whatever you plug into this is probably
Buna ne taktıysan büyük olasılıkla
gonna power it as long as it's 7.5 volts
7.5 volt olduğu sürece güç vereceğim
plus but if you plug in a 9 volt adapter
artı, ancak 9 voltluk bir adaptör taktıysanız
if you plug in a 15 volt adapter it's
15 voltluk bir adaptör taktıysanız,
going to power this board and it's safe
Bu panoya güç verecek ve güvenli
to do so
böyle yaparak
it will automatically down or up step as
otomatik olarak aşağı veya yukarı adım olacak
needed we've got 40 pin GPIO for the
biz gerekli için 40 pin GPIO var
purists and the developers we have GPIO
GPIO'larımız var ve geliştiricilerimiz var
here we've got I see infrared so if we
burada biz kızılötesi görüyorum ben öyleyse
want to use this as a infrared receiver
bunu kızılötesi alıcı olarak kullanmak istiyorum
for say a set-top box or something like
bir set üstü kutusu veya benzeri bir şey söylemek için
that
o
we've got emmc so this is where our emmc
emmc aldık, bu yüzden emmc
storage is going to plug in we've got a
depolama fişimiz takılı olacak
flip switch for our SD card versus emmc
bizim SD kart için emmc karşı çevirme anahtarı
booting we've got a TG input if we want
eğer istersen bir TG girdisine sahibiz
to plug in an OTG cable that's USB -
USB olan bir OTG kablosunu takmak için -
we've got stereo audio that's an output
bir çıkış olan stereo sese sahibiz
and of course we've also got audio on
ve elbette ses de var
the HDMI digital out one of the things
HDMI dijital şeylerden birini
that you notice with this as per the HC
Eğer HC gereğince bu konuda fark olduğunu
1 HC 2 is that there is no SOC there is
1 HC2 , SOC'nin olmadığıdır.
no CPU there is no central processing
CPU yok, merkezi işlem yok
unit shown on the board and that is
Birim gemide gösterilen ve olmasıdır
because on the flip side which you
Flip tarafında hangi çünkü
cannot see all right
tamam göremiyorum
the SOC is on the bottom of this board
SOC bu kurulun altında
and what that allows Hart kernel to do
ve bu Hart çekirdeğinin yapmasını sağlayan şeydir.
is they've created this massive heatsink
bu büyük soğutucuyı yarattılar mı
this huge aluminum heatsink which feels
hissettiren bu büyük alüminyum soğutucu
very cold to the touch is in contact
temas için çok soğuk temas halinde
with not only the the SOC so the
Sadece SOC ile değil
processor itself but also the the RAM
işlemcinin kendisi ama aynı zamanda RAM
modules which has four gigabytes of ddr3
DDR3 dört gigabayt vardır modülleri
or is it DD let me think here for a
Yoksa DD bir düşüneyim mi
second
ikinci
it's in contact with those modules
bu modüllerle temas halinde
anyways it's gonna keep it really really
neyse, gerçekten gerçekten tutacak
cool I I'm I stand corrected this is
cool Ben düzeltilmiş durumdayım bu
ddr4 Ram see I'm even astonishing myself
ddr4 Ram görmek kendimi bile şaşırtıyorum
here folks it has four gigabytes of ddr4
Burada millet o DDR4 dört giga
Ram it's 35 percent faster Ram than the
Ram yüzde 35 daha hızlı Ram
n1 way way faster than the then say the
n1 yoldan daha hızlı bir şekilde söyle
Raspberry Pi 3 now the metrics that are
Şimdi Ahududu Pi 3 olan metrikleri
provided by Hart kernel are based on the
Hart çekirdeği tarafından sağlanan
Raspberry Pi 3 model B but it's still
Ahududu Pi 3 model B ama hala
fair as a comparison and we can say that
bir karşılaştırma olarak adil ve bunu söyleyebiliriz
the CPU the performance is 20% faster
CPU performans % 20 daha hızlı
the previous generation of this and the
Bu ve önceki nesil
the heat dissipation is obviously gonna
ısı dağılımı belli ki
prevent throttling as well that's one of
boğulmayı önlemek de bunlardan biri
the key characteristics here if we
Burada temel özellikleri biz
compared this to the Raspberry Pi the
Ahududu Pi bu oranla
benchmarks of the end to it absolutely
buna sonu kriterler kesinlikle
blast past the Raspberry Pi 3 the dark
Raspberry Pi 3'ü karanlıkta fırlatın
blue that you see there that represents
orada gördüğünüzü temsil eden mavi
the PI 3 the orange on the right that's
PI 3 sağdaki turuncu
the n2 for those who are curious the xu
XU'yu merak edenler için n2
4 is the purple bar and the light blue
4 mor çubuk ve açık mavi
bar is the n1 GPU performance is 10%
Bar n1 Grafik İşlemcisi performansı% 10 olduğu
faster than the m1 so it performs very
Çok çalışır böylelikle m1 daha hızlı
very well ramp performance is easily
çok iyi rampa performansı kolayca
easily 10 times faster than the
daha kolayca 10 kat daha hızlı
Raspberry Pi 3 it's also available in a
Ahududu Pi 3 de bir kullanılabilir
2 gigabyte model so if you want less RAM
2 gigabayt model bu yüzden daha az RAM istiyorsanız
save a little bit of money you can just
para biraz kurtaracak sadece can
go with 2 gigs depending on your use
kullanımınıza bağlı olarak 2 gösteriye gidin
case and and there you have it folks
dava ve orada millet var
wonderful now I believe there is
harika şimdi Olduğuna inanıyorum
composite video out of the audio jack as
ses jakından kompozit video çıkışı
well that's something I'm being told
peki bu bana söylenen bir şey
there you go questions comments let us
işte oradaki sorularınızı yorumlayalım
know let's look at this case here I'm
hadi bu davaya bakalım işte ben
quite curious about how this can all
Tüm bu nasıl olabilir hakkında oldukça meraklı
comes together so this kind of these
bir araya geldiklerinde bu tür bunlar
typically snap together it came free
genellikle bir araya çırpın ücretsiz geldi
snapped I'm afraid to break it there we
Orada biz bunu kırmak için korkuyorum tersledi
go
gitmek
ok so when this is assembled if this is
Tamam , eğer bu monte edilmişse
like the the home cloud one then it
Evdeki bulut gibi
slides yeah exactly
evet tam olarak slaytlar
and this it does indeed it has a little
ve bu gerçekten de biraz var
more of a pronounced track than the home
evden daha belirgin bir pistten daha fazlası
cloud one so it's easier to line that up
bir tane bulut, böylece sıralamak daha kolaydır
not that the home cloud one was
bu bir ana bulut değil
difficult by any stretch as I mentioned
Bahsettiğim gibi herhangi bir streç tarafından zor
though this is a lot smaller than I was
bu benden çok daha küçük olsa da
expecting the pictures really give it
resimleri beklemek gerçekten vermek
that depiction that it's quite large and
Bu tasviri oldukça büyük olduğunu ve
I think because we're so used to the
Bence çok alışkınım.
Raspberry Pi form-factor that when we
Ahududu Pi form faktörü ne zaman biz
see all of the stuff that's included on
dahil olanların tümünü görün
this we think of this like a micro ATX
Bunu bir mikro ATX gibi düşünüyoruz.
well it's not ladies and gentlemen let
iyi o bayanlar baylar bırakmayacak
me grab
yakaladım
a Raspberry Pi 3 okay in its case I
Ahududu Pi 3 Tamam durumunda ben
don't have one out of its case right now
şu an davasından biri çıkmadı
but I'm just I just stepped off the
ama sadece ben sadece basan ediyorum
camera here just to show you so form
Kamera burada sadece bunu oluşturmak göstermek için
factor wise here's a Raspberry Pi 3 it's
akıllıca burada ahududu Pi 3 var
not much bigger actually it's not a
çok daha büyük değil aslında bir
whole lot different now it's a bit wider
çok farklı şimdi şimdi biraz daha geniş
mm-hmm Raspberry Pi 3 USB 2 but 10 over
mm-hmm Ahududu Pi 3 USB 2 ancak 10 üzeri
100 yeah Oh Droid and 2 for USB 3 Giga
USB 3 Giga 100 Ah evet Droid ve 2
bet just saying 4k 60p not 4k 60p there
bahis sadece 4k 60p değil 4k 60p var
it is beaut unboxings make me really
güzel , kutuyu açmam beni gerçekten zorlaştırıyor
want to buy I can jump right back over
üzerinde hemen geri ı atlayabilir satın almak istiyorum
to the set folks look at that that is
set millet, şuna bak
awesome not yet available to the public
harika henüz halka açık değil
however I do have an advanced
ancak ileri bir yetkim var
development board because of MEMS Linux
MEMS Linux nedeniyle geliştirme kurulu
if you aren't familiar with it yet head
bunu henüz kafa aşina değilseniz
on over to NEMS Linux comm and it's
NEMS Linux comm için üzerine gelindiğinde o ve var
going to be ported to that board I'm
o tahtaya taşınacağım ben
really excited about this board though
Bu kurul hakkında gerçekten heyecanlı olsa
it is currently supported by Ubuntu
şu anda Ubuntu tarafından desteklenmektedir
eighteen point o4 as well as Android not
onsekiz nokta o4 ve Android değil
too sure on the version on that one you
o sürümde çok emin sen
can check their forms also maverick has
Onların formlarını kontrol edebilirsiniz da başına buyruk vardır
released preliminary version of Debian
Debian'ın ön versiyonunu yayınladı
stretch for the n2 so the software
n2 için gerin böylece yazılım
support is coming very very quickly and
destek çok hızlı çok yaklaştığını ve
I think they've really nailed this one
Sanırım bunu gerçekten çivilediler
because they are provisioning
çünkü provizyon yapıyorlar
development units to the development
kalkınmaya kalkınma birimleri
community before they release it to the
Topluluk , yayınlanmadan önce
public which is a very wise idea because
çok akıllıca bir fikir olan kamu, çünkü
what what tends to happen and this is
ne olma eğiliminde ve bu
what has happened we've seen this with
ne oldu bunu gördük
some other SPC manufacturers where the
diğer bazı SPC üreticileri
boards come out and there isn't yet any
tahtalar çıkıyor ve henüz yok
software for it right so everybody goes
Yazılım doğru yüzden herkes gider için
and buys one and then the developers
ve bir geliştiriciler satın alır
have trouble buying one and so now the
bir tane satın almakta zorlanıyorum ve şimdi
developers the very people who are going
geliştiriciler gidiyor çok kişi
to be releasing software for it are
bunun için yazılım yayınlıyor olmak
having trouble getting a hold of the
sorun bir tutun almak zorunda
hardware to be able to release the
Donanımı serbest bırakabilmek için
software and the people who bought it in
yazılım ve bunu satın alan kişiler
the first run are saying
ilk koşu diyor
get it working yeah malee doesn't work
çalışmasını sağla evet malee çalışmıyor
whatever yours yeah this is the thing
seninki her neyse evet bu
so Odroid has really hit it with the end
bu yüzden Odroid gerçekten sona erdi
- it's a beautiful looking board very
- çok güzel görünümlü bir tahta
well manufactured as you know with the
bildiğiniz gibi iyi üretilmiştir
Odroid systems the benchmarks are in and
Odroid sistemleri, ölçütlerin içinde ve
the benchmarks look spectacular so I'm
kriterler muhteşem görünecek şekilde ben
very excited about that all right
Bu konuda çok heyecanlı tamam
that'll be available April 2019 is that
Nisan 2019’da satışa sunulacak
make sense
mantıklı olmak
it's coming soon yeah that's what my
yakında geliyor evet bu benim
birthday oh my goodness Dave add this to
doğum günü oh aman tanrım Dave bunu ekle
her last night
onun dün gecesi
it has 4k video output it would make a
Bir 4k video çıkışına sahip olacak
great set-top box it's got infrared so
büyük set üstü kutusu kızıl ötesi var
you can use a remote control to control
kontrol etmek için bir uzaktan kumanda kullanabilirsiniz
it
o
let's do see it's perfect it's
hadi mükemmel olduğunu görelim
absolutely perfect now that we've said
şimdi söylediklerimize göre kesinlikle mükemmel
that the community's gonna send you like
topluluğun seni göndereceği gibi
four of them what do you do with all
dördüncüsü ne yaparsın
these all of a sudden you're in
aniden bunlar sen içinde
developer check out the Odroid m2 along
geliştirici birlikte Odroid m2 kontrol
with their other products in the line
diğer ürünlerle aynı doğrultuda
cap five dot TV slash Odroid
kap beş nokta TV çizgi Odroid
[Music]
[Müzik]
[Applause]
[Alkış]